# **Mohit Saran**

# Senior Software Engineer

📞 7204728764 🛮 mohitsarano7@gmail.com 🔝 linkedin.com/in/mohitsaran

🦪 github.com/mohitsaran 👂 Bangalore, India



Over **7.5 years** of work experience in building **large-scale web Frontend** and **Backend** in leading companies in the space of **Logistics**, **Healthcare** and **Retail**. Worked in small teams to deliver a number of products while demonstrating leadership and teamwork. Skilled at continuous **integration**, **deployment** and **agile development**.

### Skills

JavaScript | HTML5 | CSS | React.Js | Python(Django) | Node(Express .Js) | Google Cloud Platform

Docker | Redis | PubSub | Microservices | Web Development | Team Management

## Professional Experience

Lowe's India, Senior Software Engineer

2019 - Present | Bengaluru, India

Lowe's Companies, Inc. is a FORTUNE® 50, home improvement company. Lowe's India focuses on technology, analytics and shared services.

#### Role & Responsibilities:

- Implementing Full stack web application development with **React**, **Redux**, **FusionCharts**, **Express.js**, **Redis**, **Docker**, **PostgreSQL**.
- Collaborating with **UX teams** to create interactive applications and developed server-side logic and APIs.
- **Reduced the manual effort** of multiple teams by **90%** by writing cron scripts that run on daily, weekly and monthly basis, to ingest the data from multiple data sources into **PostgreSQL** database.
- Determine developer requirements and specs, estimate time, and convert designs into Frontend code. Work together in teams to carry out ideas and tasks.
- Worked in **agile** framework, collaborating with business and research teams in **story grooming**, **reviewing story**, **acceptance criteria and performance metrics**.
- We created a microservices architecture application using the **Molecular Microservice** framework approach and containerised it for deployment on **Kubernetes**.

#### Technology:

React.Js, MaterialUI, Webpack, Express.js | HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python(Django) | Google Cloud Platform, Redis Server, Docker, PostgreSQL, JWT & OAuth SSO.

**Oracle Cerner,** Associate Senior Software Engineer

2017 – 2019 | Bengaluru, India

Cerner is the leading U.S. supplier of health care information technology solutions that optimize clinical and financial outcomes.

#### Role & Responsibilities:

- Created Web application with **HTML5**, **JavaScript**, **jQuery**, **Bootstrap 4**, **CSS3 & Python(Django)**. I turned the design team's **UX wireframes** and mockups into **responsive**, **interactive features**.
- Collaborated with an agile team to transition an outdated tool to a modern, **responsive**, and **interactive application**.
- Ability to handle multiple tasks and assignments concurrently in cross-functional teams and a **flexible team player** able to communicate with all levels of personnel.
- Creation of new features, mostly the UI and backend logic, in accordance with the specifications.
- Setup **celery** for **asynchronous tasks**, **redis server** for **caching static** data to load faster with web applications and **Elastic Search** to store, search, and analyse big volumes of data.

#### **Technology**

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 4 | Python[Django], PostgreSQL, Nginx, Gunicorn.

#### CityXfer, Software Engineer

2015 – 2017 | Bengaluru, India

CityXfer is an intra-city logistics company that specialises in volumetric product delivery by utilising cutting-edge technology.

#### Role & Responsibilities:

- Automated procedure by 68% which helped in managing 10x bookings without increasing Operations headcount.
- Build a technology for scale of business with 43%, which help the operation team to deliver on given SLA.
- Responsible for owning some key services and actively contributed to other services like operations, which help me to build the automated process using technology.
- Planning and doing the **root cause analysis** of various issues, giving valuable suggestion to maximize reusability of the tool.
- Build a Web application using Python [Django], HTML5, JavaScript, Bootstrap & Ajax with cross browser support/capability.

### Technology:

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap 3 | Python(Django), PostgreSQL, Apache.

## **Certificates**

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures 🛮
- Front-End Web UI Frameworks and Tools 🖸

• Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals 🛮

• Website Development with HTML & CSS

• Certified Ethical Hacker (ECC1978524063)

## Awards

Top Contributor Award, Lowes	2020
Individual Excellence Award, Lowes India	2022
Champion Award, Lowes India	2022
Team Excellence Award, Lowes India	2021
SPOT Award, Lowes India	2020
NOTT Award (Night on the town award), Cerner	2019

### **Education**

**Master of Computer Applications,** M.S. Ramaiah Institute of Technology

2012 – 2015 | Bangalore

**Bachelor of Computer Application,** *University of Rajasthan* 

2009 - 2012 | Bangalore



I'm motivated, committed and most importantly task-focused always up for trying out brand- new difficult chances and excited to contribute as a software developer.